The little light of mine - 福音歌曲
我很高兴来跟各位报告  我的土豆沙拉
Well, I am happy to report that my potato salad
又再度成为换菜大餐的热门榜首
is once again the hit of the potluck.
-很棒啊  老婆  -感觉对不起潘姆
- That's great, honey. - I feel bad for Pam Staples.
都没人要吃她的土豆沙拉
No one's touching her potato salad.
如果你觉得对不起人家  那你为什么在笑
If you feel bad, then why are you smiling?
因为有时候你妈就是个伪君子
'Cause sometimes your mommy's a big ol' hypocrite.
库珀一家好啊  你们今天好吗
Howdy, Coopers! How we doing today?
-杰夫牧师  -谢谢问候  杰夫牧师
- Pastor Jeff. - Thank you, Pastor Jeff.
你们还记得我太太萨琳娜吗
Y'all remember my wife Selena.
-你好啊  萨琳娜  -记得
- Hi, Selena. - Oh, yeah.
你们好[西语]
Que tal?
你居然娶了她吗
You're married to her?
怎么啦  是啊
Why, yes, I am.
有些事你可以想  但你不能说出来
You can think it-- you don't need to say it.
你还喜欢梅德福吗  萨琳娜
How are you liking Medford, Selena?
你喜欢梅德福吗[西语]
Como te gusta Medford?
我这辈子还没这么无聊过[西语]
她喜欢
She likes it fine.
我要去厕所抽烟了
她需要去洗手间一下
She needs to use the little girls' room.
玛丽  我能跟你谈两句吗
Mary, could I talk to you for a second?
没问题
Sure.
别担心  我会很快带她回来
Don't worry. I'll bring her right back.
不担心  不过行吧
Wouldn't worry, but okay.
好的
Okay.
他的西语好差啊
His Spanish is terrible.
她说的完全不是那么回事
That's not what she said at all.
不知道你有没有听说
I don't know if you've heard,
但我们教堂秘书
but our church secretary,
伊丽莎白·索恒奇  最近要去接受治疗
Elizabeth Sohinki, is currently seeking treatment
处理一下有关...  应该说是
for a little problem with-- shall we say--
不合法药品的成瘾症
under-the-counter medications.
所以那个谣言是真的
Oh. So that rumor's true.
她的确是整天看起来都神经兮兮
Well, she did always seem extremely alert.
神经兮兮  摇摇晃晃  大汗淋漓  反正呢
Alert, shaky, sweaty. Anyway,
我们需要有人挺身而出  接过她的职位
we need someone to step in and fill the position.
不知道你有没有兴趣考虑一下
I was wondering if you might consider it.
不只是记账
It's not just bookkeeping.
还得负责所有的修缮工作  你懂的
I'd be in charge of handling the maintenance issues-- you know,
水管电路  诸如此类
plumbing, electric, what have you.
而且我还成为了计划委员会的领导
And I'd also head the planning committee
所有的社交活动
for all the social events,
当然  也包含了三大礼
which, of course, includes the big three:
洗礼  婚礼与丧礼
baptisms, weddings, funerals.
锦上添花的部分来了
And here is the cherry on top.
教堂前面那个写着妙语的告示牌
The sign in front of the church with all the clever sayings...
"做个器官捐赠者  把心捐给耶稣"
"Be an organ donor, give your heart to Jesus"?
没错
Exactly.
你猜以后会是谁负责写
Guess whose job it would be to write those.
你
Yours.
我已经开始想了几个了
Already working on a couple.
听听这个
Listen to this.
"B1  基督徒最佳维他命"
"The best vitamin for a Christian is B1."
啥玩意
What?
B1音似"当个"
You know, be one.
当个基督徒就是最佳维他命
Like be a Christian.
B1本身也是一种维他命
And also B1 the vitamin.
听了你解释之后就好笑了
Well, now that you explained it, it's funny.
是啦  这个需要稍微想一下
Yeah. Might be a thinker.
但我还有源源不绝的各种妙语呢
But there's a lot more where that came from.
那双胞胎谁照顾
What about the twins?
我还是会每天载他们去上学
Well, I'll still get 'em off to school every day.
等他们回家了
And when they get home,
我妈可以帮我照顾他们到我回家
Mom can keep an eye on 'em till I get back.
你觉得她会同意吗
Think she'll go for it?
这还用说  我妈爱死他们了
Are you kidding? She loves 'em like crazy.
想得美啊
Fat chance.
你干嘛呀
Oh, come on.
你才干嘛呀  老娘正在人生巅峰
You come on. I'm in the prime of my life.
我得去做水上有氧跟跳萨尔萨舞
I got my water aerobics and my salsa dancing
还有保龄球队联赛
and my bowling league.
但你爱你的孙子孙女啊
But you love your grandchildren.
我也爱冰激凌  但这不代表我就会
I love ice cream, too, but I don't want to eat it
周一到周五每天下午3点吃到6点
3:00 to 6:00 five days a week.
我对你好失望
Well, I'm very disappointed.
我完全无所谓
And I'm fine with that.
你为什么不去请个保姆呢
Why don't you just get a babysitter?
这样我去赚外快不就白费了吗
Kinda defeats the purpose of making extra money.
是啊
Oh, yeah, right.
好吧  我想想
All right, let's think about it.
小乔治呢
Georgie.
他有橄榄球练习
Football practice.
而且连我在家的时候我都不放心他了
And I don't trust him when I'm home.
好吧  不过我们在这穷担心什么呢
Okay, now, what are we talking about here?
谢尔顿又聪明又有责任感
Sheldon is intelligent and responsible,
而米希...
and Missy...
是他姐姐
is his sister.
我觉得他们放学后
I think they'll be fine home alone
独自在家几个小时应该没事
all by themselves for a couple hours after school.
-你这么觉得吗  -真的
- You think? - I do.
而且呢  我觉得这对他们也有好处
As a matter of fact, I actually think it'll be great for them.
这年头的孩子就是温室的花朵
These kids today are so coddled,
我觉得你们这一辈人
I honestly think y'all are raising
把下一代的人全养成小娘炮了
a whole generation of sissies.
你这样说你的孙子们真的合适吗
Is that the way you speak about your grandchildren?
合适啊
Yes.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
我回来了
Hi.
跟你妈谈得如何
How'd it go with your mom?
她没兴趣照顾孩子们
She's not interested in watching 'em.
不想放弃她每天下午的安排
Doesn't want to give up her afternoons.
不意外  抱歉啊
Of course. Sorry.
算啦  没关系
You know what, it's okay.
时机不对
The timing wasn't right.
或许等孩子大了吧
Maybe when the kids are older.
好
Okay.
我去做晚饭吧
I guess I'll go get dinner started.
要不这样吧
How about this?
你就去接了这份工作
Go ahead and take the job.
如果接了之后发现
Yeah, if it turns out
谢尔顿与米希没办法放学后
Sheldon and Missy can't look out for themselves
好好照顾自己几个小时
for a couple hours after school,
那...
then...
我们到时候再解决那个问题
well, we'll cross that bridge when we come to it.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
是啊  其实这样对他们也有好处
Yeah. Actually, probably good for 'em.
教导他们要担起责任
Teach 'em a little responsibility.
我妈妈也是这么说的呢
That's exactly what my mom said.
是吗
Really?
那我还是一样喜欢这个主意
Well, I still like the idea.
感谢主  赐予我们桌上的食物
Thank you, God, for this food we're about to receive,
为我们的身体提供营养
and for the nourishment of our bodies,
也保佑准备这餐点的人
and bless the hands that prepared it.
阿门
Amen.
孩子们
So, kids,
我们家有件事情要讨论一下
we have a little family business to discuss.
-你怀孕了吗  -没有
- You're pregnant? - No.
-我们要养狗狗吗  -没有
- We're getting a puppy? - No.
那我很可能不会在乎
I'm not sure I care.
从下周一开始
Starting next Monday,
我会在教堂做一份全职工作
I'm gonna take a full-time job at the church.
那谁来照顾我们呢
Well, who's going to take care of us?
一切都不会有改变  我还是会做早餐
Well, nothing will change in the morning-- I'll make breakfast,
带你们俩去学校  你们放学后呢
take you both to school. Then, after school,
你们就回家  开始写作业
you'll come home, do your homework,
看看电视  玩玩具
watch TV, play with your toys
等我6点左右回家
till I come home around 6:00.
为什么姥姥不能来照顾我们呢
Well, why can't Meemaw take care of us?
-因为她不是你认为的那种人...  -乔治
- 'Cause she's not the person you think she is. - George...
你真的要独自留他们两个在家吗
You're really gonna leave these two alone?
是啊
Yes.
很大胆的选择啊
That's a brave choice.
听好了  这工作对你妈来说很重要
Look, this job is important to your mother.
我们希望你们能挺身而出  为他担起责任
We expect you both to step up and be responsible.
我可以做到
I can do that.
米希
Missy?
我考虑考虑
I'm thinking about it.
十分大胆
Very brave.
周一早上
好的  我们再来过一遍
Okay, let's go over it one more time.
家里的钥匙在前门的塑料猫头鹰下
House key's under the plastic owl by the front door.
下午的点心在冰箱里
There's after-school snacks in the fridge.
一人一份
One for each of you.
紧急联络电话就写在电话旁
Emergency numbers are right there by the phone.
急救箱就在走廊橱柜里
First aid kit is in the hall closet.
虽然你们不会用到
And you won't be needing it,
但厨房水槽下有灭火器
but under the kitchen sink is a fire extinguisher.
感觉好有意思啊
Ooh, that looks fun.
起火了才能用  也不许为了玩而放火
For fires only, and don't be starting one just to use it.
她仿佛会读心术
It's like she can read my mind.
妈妈你别担心
Don't worry, Mom.
我们不会让你失望
We'll make you proud.
我知道你不会的  宝贝
I know you will, baby.
准备好第一天上班了吗
All set for your first day?
应该好了
I believe I am.
大展拳脚吧
Go get 'em.
感谢你吵我起来啊
Thanks for waking me up.
我40分钟前就叫你起床了
I woke you up 40 minutes ago.
那你这工作做得不太好啊
Well, you didn't do a very good job.
大家再见啦
Bye, y'all.
好  行  行
Okay, yeah. Yeah.
好的  再见
Okay, later.
抱歉打扰了  佩佩   杰夫牧师有空吗
Sorry to bother you, Peg, is Pastor Jeff available?
杰夫  你有空吗
Jeff! You available?!
在打电话
On the phone.
他在打电话
He's on the phone.
我母亲戒烟的时候
You know, my mother's had some luck cutting back on the smoking
嚼尼古丁口香糖还挺有效
by chewing that nicotine gum.
正嚼着呢
Got some right here.
你有啊
So you do.
请进
Come on in.
去吧  你听到他说了吧
Go on, you heard him.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好啊  玛丽
Hey, Mare.
需要的东西都有了吧
Uh, you finding everything you need?
当然啦
Oh, you bet.
跟你说  我看了看帐
So, I've been going over the books,
我觉得我们够钱来购买
and I think we have enough money in our budget
一台个人电脑
to purchase a personal computer
来处理所有教堂事务
to handle all the church business.
好吧
Okay.
不如你把文件都留在这里
Well, uh, why don't you leave the paperwork here,
我再抽空看看
and I'll-I'll take a look at it.
没问题
Of course.
请您审阅
That's for your perusal.
没问题吧
Everything okay?
什么
What?
没问题  一切妥妥儿的
Yeah. Right as rain.
那就好
All righty.
如果你有空
Hey, if you have a minute,
我想跟你谈一下教堂前的告示牌标语
I would love to talk to you about the sign out front.
没问题啊
Yeah, sure.
一切顺利
So far so good.
有人在吗
Hello?
有人在家吗
Anybody?
他们还真不是开玩笑
They weren't kidding.
我就去偷看一眼吧
Maybe I'll just have one little peek.
你怎么不吃你的点心
How come you're not eating your snack?
我喜欢把点心当成我功课做得好的奖赏
I prefer my snack to be a reward for homework well done.
你就像一位老人
You're like an old person.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的功课是什么
What's your homework?
非欧几何
Non-Euclidean geometry.
你的呢
How about you?
"同一词"
"Symonyms."
是同义词吧
You mean synonyms.
我挺确定老师是说"同一词"
I'm pretty sure she said "Symonyms."
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
有人在外面
Someone's out there.
惨了  来到我们后院了
Oh, no. They're in the backyard.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
你们谁去给我拿个毛巾
Would one of you please get me a towel?
你为什么要在外面鬼鬼祟祟
Why were you sneaking around out there?
你吓到我们了
Yeah, you scared us.
我是来看看你们俩好不好
I was checking up on you two.
要是你们关心的话  是的  我也被吓到了
And in case you're wondering, you scared me back.
那你为什么不敲门
Well, why didn't you knock?
因为你们俩应该自己照顾好自己
Because you two are supposed to be doing this on your own.
而你不觉得我们做得到
And you don't think we can.
我当然觉得可以啦
Of course I do.
就是我告诉你妈妈
I'm the one who told your mother
你们两个可以照顾好自己的
that you were fine by yourselves in the first place.
那你为什么还来检查
Then why were you checking up on us?
这叫表里不一
That's called being two-faced.
我们自己没事的
We'll be okay on our own.
我们也得证明我们可以
Yeah, we need to prove we can do this.
好吧
All right.
我尊重你们的心
I respect that.
我也很乐意为你们保守这小小意外的秘密
And I'm happy to keep this little incident a secret.
是吗  我要告诉大家
Really? I'm telling everyone.
太好笑了
It was hilarious.
我要去打保龄球了
I'm going bowling.
我们一开始交往时  一切都很美妙
When we first started dating, everything was wonderful.
刚交往的确都会很美妙啊
That's when it is wonderful.
我们一结婚问题就统统跑出来了
All the problems started once we got married.
婚姻的确是会对感情造成问题
Well, marriage will do that to a relationship.
我给萨琳娜一张信用卡
I-I got Selena a credit card
让她添购家用物品时用
to make small purchases for the house.
比如说咖啡机  吸尘器
You know... ...coffee maker, DustBuster.
你知道她干嘛了吗
You know what she did?
她跑去电器用品店
She went to that Sharper Image store
买了一张按摩椅
and she bought a massage chair.
我在商场也坐过一次
Oh, I sat in one of those at the mall.
超舒服啊
It was terrific.
要两千刀呢
It's $2,000.
在看过你的帐之后
Oh. Well, seeing as I know how much you make,
我知道你买不起这个
you can't afford that.
我...
I... uh-uh.
在所有小孩能碰到的
Of all the afflictions
危险磨难中  有一个危险之王
that can befall a child, one reigns supreme.
超越擦破膝盖与被纸割伤
Beyond scraped knees and paper cuts,
没有什么在全球孩子的心里造成的恐惧
nothing strikes fear into the hearts of kids around the world
能超越倒刺
like a splinter.
不要啊
No!
我被倒刺刺到了
I've got a splinter!
所以呢
So?
所以这是紧急事态啊
So, it's an emergency!
快打给姥姥
Call Meemaw!
冷静好吗
Oh, calm down.
-我们自己能搞定  -我们不能
- We can take care of this. - No, we can't!
谢尔顿  如果连个小倒刺都搞不定
Sheldon, if we can't handle a little splinter,
他们永远也不会再让我们自己在家了
they're never gonna leave us alone again.
你说得对
You're right.
那我们该怎么做
So, what do we do?
让我看看
Let me see it.
哎哟  还挺深的
Oh, boy. That's a deep one.
痛得很厉害呢
Hey, it's throbbing really bad.
妈通常都是用镊子夹出来
Mom would take it out with tweezers.
那我们上哪找镊子
Well, where would we find tweezers?
看看这里有什么工具
Let's see what we got.
邦迪
Band-Aids...
棉球
cotton balls.
什么是"纱扑"
What's "Gowz"?
是纱布  而你连这是什么都不知道
It's gauze, and the fact that you don't know that
真是把希望之火又灭了不少
is not filling me with hope.
妈妈会把镊子收在哪里呢
Where would Mom keep the tweezers?
-她有时候也会用针挑出倒刺啊  -不行
- Sometimes she uses a needle on splinters. - ?No.
不许用针  除了针什么都可以
No needles. Anything but needles.
等等  她的化妆包里有镊子
Wait, she has tweezers in her makeup bag.
她用镊子来拔眉毛
She plucks her eyebrows with them.
有时候还拔她的小胡子
And sometimes her mustache.
找到了吗
Anything?
没有
Nope.
等等
Wait.
或许是收在他们房里
Maybe they're in her room.
我们不允许进爸妈的房里
We're not allowed to go in Mom and Dad's room.
你要我用针帮你挑吗
Want me to get the needle?
我们速战速决吧
Let's make this quick.
你为什么要小声说话
Why are you whispering?
大家在不乖的时候就是这么说话的
That's how people speak when they're being naughty.
这我就不会知道了
I wouldn't know.
因为我没有一刻是乖的
I'm naughty all the time.
你真的不进来吗
You're really not coming in?
不进  但你做得不错
No. But you're doing great.
怎么了
What's wrong?
这样真的好不乖啊
This really is naughty.
我跟你说了
I told you.
没有看到呢
I don't see anything.
就看到一本圣经跟手电筒
There's just a Bible and a flashlight.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
接起来  但语气保持冷静
Answer it but sound calm.
你好
Hello.
你好啊  是爸爸
Hey, it's Dad.
你们俩还好吗
How you guys doing?
我们很好
We're great.
那就太好了
Glad to hear it.
我在看电视
I'm watching TV,
谢尔顿在安静地阅读
and Sheldon's reading quietly.
我就知道你们俩没问题
I knew you could handle this.
-爸爸为你们感到骄傲  -其实呢
- I'm proud of you. - You know what?
我们也为自己感到骄傲
I'm proud of us, too.
好啦  宝贝闺女
Okay, baby doll,
我几个小时后就回家了
I'll be home in a couple hours.
今晚不回家也没事  我们可以的
Stay out all night. We got this.
什...  我也爱你们
Wha... Love you, too.
真是太紧张了
That was intense.
我觉得我不适合这种留守儿童的生活
I don't think I'm cut out for this latchkey life.
这次换你去接
You answer it this time.
不可以  我现在应该在安静读书才对啊
I can't; I'm supposed to be reading quietly.
去接  谢尔顿
Answer it, Sheldon.
我要接也不进去接
Well, I'm not going in there.
您好  这里是库珀家
Hello. Cooper residence.
我是谢尔顿
Sheldon speaking.
谢利
Hey, Shelly.
是你啊  妈妈
Oh, hello, Mom.
你今天过得好吗
How's your day going?
谢利
Shelly?
谢利  谢利  你在吗
Shelly? Shelly? You there?
我在啊
Yes, I'm here.
她想知道我今天好吗
She wants to know how my day's going.
你就回今天好啊
Say it's going good.
我不能这么说
I can't say that.
为什么
Why not?
因为这样文法不对
It's bad grammar.
那你应该怎么说才对
How are you supposed to say it?
"我今天很好"
"It's going well."
你好就好
Oh, that's nice.
我得继续工作了
I've got to get back to work,
但妈咪很爱你跟米希哦
but I love you and miss you very much.
好
Okay.
我处理得十分妥当
I handled that really well.
有空吗
Got a minute?
有啊  请进
Sure, come on in.
我想跟你道歉
I just wanted to apologize.
让你听我倾诉这些个人烦恼是不对的
I-It was wrong of me to unload my personal business on you.
而且你还是第一天来上班呢
Here it is, your first day and all.
没事啦
Oh, that's fine.
我十分乐意听人倾诉
Always happy to lend an ear.
那就好  因为我还没说完全部呢
Great, 'cause I didn't tell you everything.
真的吗  你已经说了非常多了呢
Really? 'Cause you told me a lot.
今天早上我趁萨琳娜去洗澡的时候
This morning, while Selena was in the shower,
我翻了她的皮包  把信用卡拿回来了
I went through her purse and I took the credit card.
天啊
Oh, my.
你觉得这算偷吗  还是我做的是正确的选择
Now, do you think that's stealing, or is it doing the right thing?
让我们免于破产之类的问题
You know, saving us from bankruptcy and whatnot?
这事还挺复杂的
Wow. Um, yeah, that's complicated.
翻她钱包这件事  应该是不对的
Um... going through her purse-- probably wrong,
不过换个角度来看...
but on the other hand...
没别的角度了
...well, there is no other hand.
你不能做这种事情
You can't be doing things like that
然后还想有正常的婚姻关系啊
and have a healthy marriage.
你为什么不跟她谈谈呢
Why don't you just talk to her?
跟她说说你的经济情况
Explain your financial situation?
这个嘛...
That...
现在还要关上门谈了吗
Oh, we're closing the door now, okay.
跟她谈有些困难
That's not so easy.
因为语言障碍吗
Because of the language barrier?
除此之外  在我们刚交往那会儿
That, and I implied, when we were dating,
我暗示过我...  颇有资产
that I was... well-to-do.
杰夫牧师  你怎么能做这种事呢
Oh, Pastor Jeff, why would you do that?
你也见过她了
You saw her.
她就是那一种
Uh, she is the kind of woman
会让人忍不住想做坏事的女人啊
that can make a man do bad things.
这话...  我就不知道作何评价了
Well, I... I don't know what to say to that.
或许你该祈祷吧
Maybe you ought to pray on it.
你说得对
You're right.
你说的完全正确
You're absolutely right.
我现在就去
I'll do that now.
我也会祈祷
I'll do the same.
谢谢
Thank you.
主啊  请求您赐我力量
God, please give me the strength
让我能不说出杰夫牧师的超级大八卦
to not spread this juicy gossip about Pastor Jeff.
阿门
Amen.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
《我  机器人》
我在安静地阅读  免得之后我得说谎
I'm reading quietly, so I don't have to lie about it later.
找到啦
Found 'em.
镊子吗
The tweezers?
妈妈的针跟放大镜
Mom's needles and her magnifying glass.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
你好歹让我试试看嘛
Let me at least try.
不行
No.
别像个没胆的孩子好吗
You're being a baby.
你说什么我都不会改变主意
Nothing you can say will change my mind.
如果伤口感染并开始发绿
What if it gets infected and turns green
最后只能截肢呢
and they have to cut it off?
我觉得应该麻痹了
I think it's numb.
很好  把手放上来
Great, put your hand out.
等等  你打算怎么给针消毒
Wait, how do you plan on sterilizing the needle?
妈妈都用火柴烧一烧
Mom uses a lit match.
小孩子不许玩火柴
We're not allowed to play with matches.
那还有什么有用
What else would work?
酒精
Alcohol.
把你的手指放进去
Stick your finger in there.
我负责给针消毒
I'll do the needle.
好吧  希望我不会醉
Okay. I hope I don't get drunk.
要泡多久才完成消毒啊
How long till you're sterile?
不知道
I don't know,
但我开始有点晕乎了
but I'm getting lightheaded.
无论发生什么事  别乱动
No matter what happens, hold still.
我不行
I can't do it.
-你可以的  -不  我不行
- Yes, you can. - No, I can't.
就让我挑出来吧
Just let me get it.
万一你手滑一针戳进我眼睛怎么办
What if you slip and stab me in the eye?
我才不会手滑
I'm not gonna slip.
你想想每次都是谁赢了...
Who always wins when we play...
马上回来
Be right back.
在1989年  布雷德利公司
In 1989 the Milton Bradley Company
在市场上发行了许多桌游
had dozens of board games on the market,
但只有一款你能扮演医生
but only one where you were the doctor.
手术
《手术》游戏内包含了
Operation came complete
一个能发光的警告红鼻子
with a red light-up nose,
13块塑料人体部位让玩家移出
13 plastic body parts for players to remove
以及最重要的  一支真实的镊子
and, most importantly, one pair of genuine tweezers.
我姐姐用小孩的桌游工具
My sister performed a medical procedure using
完成了一场真实手术
a children's board game,
而我勇敢地坐着保持不动
while I bravely sat very still.
或许你可以说那天我们家出了两位勇者
I guess you could say there were two heroes that day.
-我回来啦  -我们在客厅
- Hello? - In here.
为什么厨房一股威士忌味
Why does the kitchen smell like whiskey?
问她
Ask her.
我的老天爷啊
Oh, dear Lord!
等你听完我对姥姥干嘛了你再惊讶
Wait till you hear what I did to Meemaw.